Julia Newman: "Into the Fire" Research Materials: Partial Inventory ALBA.226
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Julia Newman "Into the Fire" Research Material
1990s-2002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Newman, Julia
ALBA.226
20.5 Linear Feet (21 boxes)
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of drafts of scripts, interview transcripts, correspondence, references files, photocopies of Spanish Civil War-era clippings and other documents, and audio-visual material compiled in the course of research and production for "Into the Fire: American Women in the Spanish Civil War" (Exemplary Films; produced and directed by Julia Newman; released 2002). The collection includes research material drawn from a wide variety of archives in the U.S. and Europe, some of it focused narrowly on U.S. women's participation and some covering the whole spectrum of Spanish Civil War history.
An inventory of Boxes 2-11 of the collection, containing video and film material used in production of the film is available (see Box List). The remaining boxes contain paper records, photographs, graphics, and audio materials.
Appraisal
Some photostats of newspaper clippings and duplicate photographs were discarded in April 2017.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Tamiment Library & Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives for more information and to schedule an appointment, tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access to audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact special.collections@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
- Series I: Julia Newman: "Into the Fire" Resources, 366004
  - Interview: "Irv and Frieda Weissman Part 1." 34-minute digital audio tape (DAT)., Jan 25, 1993; cuid33095; 366009 (Box 2, Item 226-001)
  - Interview: "Irv and Frieda Weissman Part 2." digital audio tape (DAT)., Undated; cuid33096; 366010 (Box 2, Item 226-002)
  - Voice Over: "Civil War Announcer Trk." digital audio tape (DAT)., Oct 16, 1992; cuid33097; 366011 (Box 2, Item 226-003)
  - Archive Sound Element: "The Lincoln Brigade." 64-minute digital audio tape (DAT). (Original from National Sound.), Mar 16, 1999; cuid33098; 366012 (Box 2, Item 226-004)
  - Archive Sound Element: "The Lincoln Brigade." 64-minute digital audio tape (DAT). (Original from National Sound.), Mar 16, 1999; cuid33099; 366015 (Box 2, Item 226-005)
  - Voice Over: "The Spanish Civil War Tape 2 of 2." 125-minute digital audio tape (DAT)., May 31, 2001; cuid33100; 366016 (Box 2, Item 226-006)
  - Voice Over: "The Spanish Civil War Tape 1 of 2." 125-minute digital audio tape (DAT)., May 31, 2001; cuid33101; 366017 (Box 2, Item 226-007)
  - Music: "Espana 1936-1939 Vol. 2." Audio cassette., cuid33102; 366018 (Box 2, Item 226-008)
  - Audio: "The Lincoln Brigade." Digital tape recording system (DTRS)., Mar 16, 1999; cuid33103; 366019 (Box 2, Item 226-009)
  - Audio: "The Lincoln Brigade." Digital audio tape (DAT)., Apr 19, 1999; cuid33104; 366020 (Box 2, Item 226-010)
  - Voice over: "The Lincoln Brigade." 94-minute digital audio tape (DAT)., Apr 19, 1999; cuid33105; 366021 (Box 2, Item 226-011)
  - Voice over: "The Lincoln Brigade." 64-minute digital audio tape (DAT). (Original from National Sound.), Mar 16, 1999; cuid33106; 366022 (Box 2, Item 226-012)
  - Interview: "Irene Goldin Spiegel Vienna 11/95." 90-minute audio cassette., Nov 1995; cuid33107; 366023 (Box 2, Cd 226-013, Item 226-013)
  - Music: "Songs of the SCW vol 1 & 2." 60-minute audio cassette., Undated; cuid33108; 366024 (Box 2, Item 226-014)
  - Interview: "Lini DeVries 1 & 2." 90-minute audio cassette., Undated; cuid33109; 366025 (Box 2, Cd 226-015, Item 226-015)
  - Interview: "Hilda Bell Roberts #3 Ruth Davidow 1 & 2." 90-minute audio cassette., Undated; cuid33110; 366026 (Box 2, Item 226-016)
  - Interview: "Hilda Bell Roberts #3 Ruth Davidow 1 & 2." 90-minute audio cassette., Undated; cuid33111; 366027 (Box 2, Item 226-016)
  - Interview: "Gustleisler and Ray Morantz 3." Audio cassette., Undated; cuid33112; 366028 (Box 2, Item 226-017)
  - Interview: "Gustleisler and Ray Morantz 1." Audio cassette., Undated; cuid33113; 366029 (Box 2, Item 226-018)
  - Interview: "Hilda Bell Roberts #1 & 2." 90-minute audio cassette., Undated; cuid33114; 366030 (Box 2, Item 226-019)
  - Interview: "Ruth Davidow 3 & 4." 90-minute audio cassette., Undated; cuid33115; 366031 (Box 2, Item 226-020)
  - Interview: "Lini DeVries 2 & 3." 90-minute audio cassette., Undated; cuid33116; 366032 (Box 2, Cd 226-021, Item 226-021)
  - Interview: "Edna Rome 1 & 2." 90-minute audio cassette., Undated; cuid33117; 366033 (Box 2, Item 226-022)
  - Interview: "Gustleisler and Ray Morantz 2." Audio cassette., Undated; cuid33118; 366034 (Box 2, Item 226-023)
  - Interview: "Toby Jensky 1, Bill Miller 3." 90-minute audio cassette., Undated; cuid33119; 366035 (Box 2, Item 226-024)
  - Music: "Espana 1936-1939 Vol. 2." 90-minute audio cassette., cuid33120; 366036 (Box 2, Item 226-025)
  - Interview: "Esther Silverstein Blanc 1, Milt Wolff 4." Audio cassette., Undated; cuid33121; 366037 (Box 2, Item 226-026)
  - Interview: "Esther Silverstein Blanc tape 2." High-band Video8 (Hi-8)., Undated; cuid33122; 366038 (Box 2, Item 226-027)
  - Interview: "Esther Silverstein Blanc." High-band Video8 (Hi-8)., Undated; cuid33123; 366039 (Box 2, Item 226-028)
  - Voice over: "Spanish Civil War." 125-minute digital audio tape (DAT)., Jun 1, 2001; cuid33124; 366040 (Box 2, Item 226-029)
  - Interview: "Evelyn Hutchins #1." Audio CD., Undated; cuid33125; 366041 (Box 2, Item 226-030)
  - Interview: "Evelyn Hutchins 1-2." Audio CD., Undated; cuid33126; 366178 (Box 2, Item 226-031)
  - Interview: "Evelyn Hutchins 3-4." Audio CD., Undated; cuid33127; 366179 (Box 2, Item 226-032)
  - Interview: "Evelyn Hutchins 5." Audio CD., Undated; cuid33128; 366180 (Box 2, Item 226-033)
  - Interview: "Martha Gellhorn Speaking from Madrid." Audio CD., Undated; cuid33129; 366181 (Box 2, Item 226-034)
  - Interview: "Helen [Freeman Feinberg] Disc 6." Audio CD., Undated; cuid33130; 366182 (Box 2, Item 226-035)
  - Interview: "Irene [Goldin Spiegel] 1 CD2 1st part." Audio CD., Undated; cuid33131; 366183 (Box 2, Item 226-036)
  - Interview: "Celia Greenspan." Audio CD., Undated; cuid33132; 366184 (Box 2, Item 226-037)
  - Interview: "Evelyn Hutchins 2&3 CD#3." Audio CD., Undated; cuid33133; 366185 (Box 2, Item 226-038)
  - Interview: "CD 1." Audio CD., cuid33134; 366186 (Box 2, Item Undated)
  - Interview: "Salaria Kee (a.k.a. Salaria Kea, later O'Reilly)." Audio CD., Undated; cuid33135; 366187 (Box 2, Item 226-040)
  - Interview: "CD 4." Audio CD., Undated; cuid33136; 366188 (Box 2, Item 226-041)
  - Interview: "Irene [Goldin Spiegel] 1 CD2 1st part." Audio CD., Undated; cuid33137; 366198 (Box 2, Item 226-042)
  - Text: Unidentified 3.5-inch floppy disk., Nov 27, 2000; cuid33138; 366199 (Box 2, Item 226-043)
  - Text: "Silverstein, Greenspan, Gellhorn Hutchins, DeVries and Davidow." 3.5-inch floppy disk., Nov 21, 2000; cuid33139; 366234 (Box 2, Item 226-044)
  - Interview text: "Evelyn Hutchins." 3.5-inch floppy disk., Nov 10, 2000; cuid33140; 366235 (Box 2, Item 226-045)
  - Interview: "Salaria Kee (a.k.a. Salaria Kea, later O'Reilly)." 3.5-inch floppy disk., Dec 11, 2000; cuid33141; 366236 (Box 2, Item 226-046)
  - Interview text: "Dr. M. Broggi-Valles translated Transcript." 3.5-inch floppy disk., Undated; cuid33142; 366238 (Box 2, Item 226-047)
  - Interview text: "Celia Greenspan." 3.5-inch floppy disk., Dec 15, 2000; cuid33143; 366239 (Box 2, Item 226-048)
  - Music: "SCW Songs." 60-minute audio cassette., Undated; cuid33144; 366240 (Box 2, Item 226-049)
  - Interview: "[Rebecca] Becky Shulman Durem 1 & 2." Audio cassette., Undated; cuid33145; 366242 (Box 2, Item 226-050)
  - Interview: "Rebecca Shulman Durem LA." 90-minute audio cassette., May 14, 1993; cuid33146; 366243 (Box 2, Item 226-051)
  - Voice over: "Ann Taft Narrative- Julie." 65-minute digital audio tape (DAT)., Aug 13, 2001; cuid33147; 366244 (Box 2, Item 226-052)
  - Voice over: "Alice Wagnon." 65-minute digital audio tape (DAT)., May 15, 2001; cuid33148; 366247 (Box 2, Item 226-053)
  - Voice over: "LDV." 65-minute digital audio cassette., Jun 4, 2001; cuid33149; 366248 (Box 2, Item 226-054)
  - Voice over: "MG." 65-minute digital audio tape (DAT)., Apr 24, 2001; cuid33150; 366249 (Box 2, Item 226-055)
  - Voice over: "Spanish Civil War." Audio cassette., Jun 1, 2001; cuid33151; 366250 (Box 2, Item 226-056)
  - Interview: "Their Cause Was Liberty [with Frieda and Irv Weissman]." 110-minute audio cassette., Jan 25, 1993; cuid33152; 366251 (Box 2, Item 226-057)
  - Interview: "Their Cause Was Liberty [with Freida and Irv Weissman]." 90-minute audio cassette., Jan 25, 1993; cuid33153; 366252 (Box 2, Item 226-058)
  - Interview: "Salaria Kee (a.ka. Salaria Kea) O'Reilly 1 & 2." 90-minute audio cassette., Undated; cuid33154; 366255 (Box 2, Item 226-059)
  - Interview: "Salaria Kee (a.ka. Salaria Kea) O'Reilly 3 & 4 Pat O'Reilly 1." 90-minute audio cassette., Undated; cuid33155; 366256 (Box 2, Cd 226-060, Item 226-060)
  - Interview: "Salaria Kee (a.ka. Salaria Kea) O'Reilly 3 & 4 Pat O'Reilly 1." 90-minute audio cassette., Undated; cuid33156; 366257 (Box 2, Item 226-061)
  - Interview: "Salaria Kee (a.ka. Salaria Kea) O'Reilly 1 & 2." 90-minute audio cassette., Undated; cuid33157; 366258 (Box 2, Item 226-062, Cd 226-062)
  - Audio: "Helen Freeman Feinberg Sleepy Lullaby." 90-minute audio cassette., May 14, 1993; cuid33158; 366259 (Box 2, Item 226-063)
  - Interview: "Mildred Rackley Simon, 1 & 2." 90-minute audio cassette., Undated; cuid33159; 366260 (Box 2, Cd 226-064, Item 226-064)
  - Voice over: "ALB VO M.R. Simon 3 ED Bender 2 & 2." 90-minute audio cassette., Undated; cuid33160; 366261 (Box 2, Cd 226-065, Item 226-065)
  - Interview: "Ossie Davis." 60-minute mini digital video (mini DV)., Undated; cuid33161; 366262 (Box 2, Item 226-066)
  - Interview: "Becky [Rebecca Durem] Shulman." 60-minute mini digital video (mini DV)., Undated; cuid33162; 366263 (Box 2, Item 226-067)
  - Video: "Len Levenson Volunteer P65." 60-minute mini digital video (mini DV)., Undated; cuid33163; 366264 (Box 2, Item 226-068)
  - Interview: "Women Brig. #1 Ruth Davidow." 60-minute mini digital video (mini DV)., Feb 23, 1997; cuid33164; 366265 (Box 2, Item 226-069)
  - Interview: "Women Brig. #2 Ruth Davidow." 60-minute mini digital video (mini DV)., Feb 23, 1997; cuid33165; 366266 (Box 2, Item 226-070)
  - Stills: "SCW." 700MB CD-R., Dec 19, 2000; cuid33166; 366267 (Box 2, Item 226-071)
  - Stills: "SCW Slide Scans." 700MB CD-R., Mar 12, 2001; cuid33167; 366268 (Box 2, Item 226-072)
  - Stills: "Columbia Rare Scans Online Verison 1 of 2." 700MB CD-R. (Original from Columbia University.), Dec 10, 2001; cuid33168; 366272 (Box 2, Item 226-073)
  - Stills: "Columbia Rare Scans Online Verison 2 of 2." 700MB CD-R. (Original from Columbia University.), Dec 10, 2001; cuid33169; 366273 (Box 2, Item 226-074)
  - Stills: "Columbia Rare Scans disk 3/4." 700MB CD-R. (Original from Columbia University.), Aug 21, 2001; cuid33170; 366274 (Box 2, Item 226-075)
  - Interview: "Irene [Goldin Spiegel] 1." 30-minute. Video Betacam SP., Nov 29, 1995; cuid33171; 366298 (Box 3, Item 226-076)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Recorded in the PAL broadcast standard. Preservation note: This tape was not digitized. It is believed to be the same content as alba226_175.
  - Interview: "Irene [Goldin Spiegel] 2." 30-minute. Video Betacam SP., Nov 29, 1995; cuid33172; 366299 (Box 3, Item 226-077)
  - Interview: "Irene [Goldin Spiegel] 3." 30-minute. Video Betacam SP., Nov 29, 1995; cuid33173; 366300 (Box 3, Item 226-078)
  - Interview: "Irene [Goldin Spiegel] 4." 30-minute. Video Betacam SP., Nov 29, 1995; cuid33174; 366301 (Box 3, Item 226-079)
  - Interview: "Irene [Goldin Spiegel] 5." 30-minute. Video Betacam SP., Nov 30, 1995; cuid33175; 366302 (Box 3, Item 226-080)
  - Interview: "Irene [Goldin Spiegel] 6." 30-minute. Video Betacam SP., Nov 30, 1995; cuid33176; 366303 (Box 3, Item 226-081)
  - Interview: "Irene [Goldin Spiegel] 7." 30-minute. Video Betacam SP., Nov 30, 1995; cuid33177; 366304 (Box 3, Item 226-082)
  - Interview: "Irene [Goldin Spiegel] 8." 30-minute. Video Betacam SP., Nov 30, 1995; cuid33178; 366305 (Box 3, Item 226-083)
  - Interview: "Irene [Goldin Spiegel] 9." 30-minute. Video Betacam SP., Nov 30, 1995; cuid33179; 366306 (Box 3, Item 226-084)
  - Archival footage: "Interview with Martha Gellhorn BBC Omnibus." 30-minute. Video Betacam SP. (Original from BBC Omnibus.), Undated; cuid33180; 366307 (Box 2, Item 226-085)
  - Archival footage: "Items for Exemplary Films items 1 & 2." 10-minute. Video Betacam SP. (Original from BBC Omnibus.), Undated; cuid33181; 366308 (Box 3, Item 226-086)
  - Archival footage: "Fox Movietone News Spanish Civil War tape 1." 30-minute. Video Betacam SP. (Originally from Fox Movietone.), Undated; cuid33182; 366309 (Box 3, Item 226-087)
  - Archival footage: "Fox Movietone News Spanish Civil war tape 3." 10-minute. Video Betacam SP. (Originally from Fox Movietone.), Undated; cuid33183; 366312 (Box 3, Item 226-088)
  - Archival footage: "Fox Movietone News Spanish Civil war tape 6." 30-minute. Video Betacam SP. (Originally from Fox Movietone.), Undated; cuid33184; 366313 (Box 3, Item 226-089)
  - Interview: "Helen Freeman Feinberg 1." 30-minute. Video Betacam SP., Dec 5, 1993; cuid33185; 366314 (Box 3, Item 226-090)
  - Interview: "Helen Freeman Feinberg 2." 30-minute. Video Betacam SP., Dec 5, 1993; cuid33186; 366315 (Box 3, Item 226-091)
  - Interview: "Helen Freeman Feinberg 3." 30-minute. Video Betacam SP., Dec 5, 1993; cuid33187; 366316 (Box 3, Item 226-092)
  - Archival footage: "Filmoteca." 30-minute. Video Betacam SP. (Original from Filmoteca.), Dec 18, 2001; cuid33188; 366317 (Box 3, Item 226-093)
  - Archival footage: "Filmoteca." 20-minute. Video Betacam SP. (Original from Filmoteca.), Undated; cuid33189; 366318 (Box 3, Item 226-094)
  - Archival footage: "Filmoteca." 10-minute. Video Betacam SP. (Original from Filmoteca.), Undated; cuid33190; 366322 (Box 3, Item 226-095)
  - Archival footage: "Filmoteca." 10-minute. Video Betacam SP. (Original from Filmoteca.), Dec 21, 2001; cuid33191; 366323 (Box 3, Item 226-096)
  - archival footage: "Espana." 10-minute. Video Betacam SP., Oct 24, 2001; cuid33192; 366324 (Box 3, Item 226-097)
  - Archival footage: "Leves avant le Jour 3 extraits." 10-minute. Video Betacam SP. (Original from Cine-Archives.), Jan 11, 2001; cuid33193; 366326 (Box 3, Item 226-098)
  - Video: "Spanish Civil War TRXF from Mini DV #1 Selects Spain 1996." 20-minute. Betacam SP., Undated; cuid33194; 366327 (Box 3, Item 226-099)
  - Video: "Spanish Civil War TRXF from Mini DV #2 Selects Spain 1996." 20-minute. Betacam SP., Undated; cuid33195; 366328 (Box 3, Item 226-100)
  - Video: "Spanish Civil War TRXF from Mini DV #3." 20-minute. Betacam SP., Undated; cuid33196; 366329 (Box 3, Item 226-101)
  - Video: "Spanish Civil War TRXF from Mini DV #4." 20-minute. Betacam SP., Undated; cuid33197; 366330 (Box 3, Item 226-102)
  - Video: "International Brigades TRXF Mini DV to Beta #2 Spain 1996." 20-minute. Betacam SP., Apr 22, 1999; cuid33198; 366331 (Box 3, Item 226-103)
  - Archival footage: "BENICASIM Abraham Lincoln Brigade." 30-minute. Video Betacam SP., Dec 10, 1997; cuid33199; 366332 (Box 3, Item 226-104)
  - Archival footage: "Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archival Films." 30-minute. Video Betacam SP., Dec 10, 1997; cuid33200; 366333 (Box 3, Item 226-105)
  - Archival footage: "ALBA SCW- Cuban Film 1948." 20-minute. Video Betacam SP., Dec 10, 1997; cuid33201; 366334 (Box 3, Item 226-106)
  - Video: "SCW Refuge." 30-minute. Betacam SP., Dec 10, 1997; cuid33202; 366335 (Box 3, Item 226-107)
  - Archival footage: "Spanish Civil War Add'l Footage from Moscow." 20-minute. Video Betacam SP., Undated; cuid33203; 366336 (Box 3, Item 226-108)
  - Archival footage: "SCW Russian Footage-NTSC." 30-minute. Video Betacam SP., Undated; cuid33204; 366344 (Box 3, Item 226-109)
  - Archival footage. "SCW Russia Footage-PAL." 30-minute. Video Betacam SP., Undated; cuid33205; 366345 (Box 3, Item 226-110)
  - Archival footage. "SCW Add'l Footage from Moscow." 30-minute. Video Bteacam SP., Apr 14, 1999; cuid33206; 366346 (Box 3, Item 226-111)
  - Archival Footage: "The Mooney Project Selected Clips." 30-minute. Video Betacam SP., Nov 20, 2001; cuid33207; 366347 (Box 3, Item 226-112)
  - Archival footage: "Peter Miller Documentary Films Slected Segments." 10-minute. Video Betacam SP., Jun 12, 2000; cuid33208; 366348 (Box 3, Item 226-113)
  - Archival footage: "Celia Seborer Footage and Bethune Photo." 30-minute. Video Betcam SP. (Original from CBC.), Oct 31, 2001; cuid33209; 366349 (Box 3, Item 226-114)
  - Archival Footage: "SCW UCLA Film and TV Archive." 30-minute. Video Betacam Sp. (Original from UCLA Film and TV Archive.), Undated; cuid33210; 366350 (Box 3, Item 226-115)
  - Archival footage: "Lincoln Brigade Footage from 1937." 20-minute. Video Betacam SP. (Original from UCLA Film and TV Archive.), Feb 4, 1999; cuid33211; 366351 (Box 4, Item 226-116)
  - Archival footage: "Hineni International Brigades." 5-minute. Video Betacam SP., Oct 30, 2001; cuid33212; 366352 (Box 4, Item 226-117)
  - Promo: "Their Cause was Liberty." 20-minute. Video Betacam SP., Apr 25, 2000; cuid33213; 366375 (Box 4, Item 226-118)
  - Archival footage: "The Goodfight Archival Footage 1 of 2." 30-minute. Video Betacam SP., Undated; cuid33214; 366376 (Box 4, Item 226-119)
  - Archival footage: "The Goodfight Archival Footage 2 of 2. 30-minute. Video Betacam SP., Undated; cuid33215; 366377 (Box 4, Item 226-120)
  - Archival footage: "Celia Greenspan." 30-minute. Video Betacam SP. (Original from CBC.), Nov 9, 2001; cuid33216; 366378 (Box 4, Item 226-121)
  - Archival footage: "Actualite Guerre D'Espagne." 10-minute. Video Betacam SP. (Original from Cinemateque Gaumont.), Undated; cuid33217; 366386 (Box 4, Item 226-122)
  - Archival footage: "Guernica Guerre D'Espagne." 30-minute. Video Betacam SP. (Original from Cinemateque Gaumont.), Oct 24, 2001; cuid33218; 366387 (Box 4, Item 226-123)
  - Archival footage: "SCW." 30-minute. Video Betacam SP. (Original from UCLA Film and TV Archives.), Undated; cuid33219; 366388 (Box 4, Item 226-124)
  - Archival footage: "Civil War in Spain." 20-minute. Video Betacam SP. (Original from Greinberg Film Libraries.), Mar 7, 2000; cuid33220; 366389 (Box 4, Item 226-125)
  - Archival footage: "SCW 1972." 20-minute. Video Betacam SP., Mar 4, 1997; cuid33221; 366390 (Box 4, Item 226-126)
  - Video: "A. Vega Kunhardt Working Material." 30-minute. Betacam SP., Undated; cuid33222; 366391 (Box 4, Item 226-127)
  - Archival footage: "Interbrigades International Brigades Excerpts from Moscow." 10-minute. Video Betacam SP., Undated; cuid33223; 366392 (Box 4, Item 226-128)
  - Video: "Brigadista Poster Barcelona Catalonion." 20-minute. Betacam SP., Mar 11, 1997; cuid33224; 366393 (Box 4, Item 226-129)
  - Interview: "Irene's [Goldin Spiegel] SB in Madrid." 30-minute. Video Betacam SP., Undated; cuid33225; 366395 (Box 4, Item 226-130, Box Digitized Access Files, File alba226_cuid33225)
  - Video: "4403 Selects." Betacam SP. (Original from Fast Images.), Oct 18, 2001; cuid33226; 366396 (Box 4, Item 226-131)
  - Archival footage: "Their Cause was Liberty." 10-minute. Video Betacam SP. (Original from Getty Images.), Undated; cuid33227; 366412 (Box 4, Item 226-132)
  - Stills: "Still x-fer for Lincoln Brigade." 30-minute. Video Betacam SP., Feb 2001; cuid33228; 366413 (Box 4, Item 226-133)
  - Archival footage: "Archive Films." 20-minute. Video Betacam SP., Undated; cuid33229; 366414 (Box 4, Item 226-134)
  - Stills: "Brandeis Stills." 30-minute. Video Betacam SP., Oct 26, 2000; cuid33230; 366415 (Box 4, Item 226-135)
  - Promo: "Their Cause was Liberty." 32-minute digital Betacam video., May 20, 1999; cuid33231; 366416 (Box 4, Item 226-136)
  - Video: "Gloria Berrocal Spanish Women." 60-minute. Video Betacam SP., Feb 2, 2001; cuid33232; 366417 (Box 5, Item 226-137)
  - Video: "Lincoln Brigade Women Brig #1." 60-minute. Betacam SP., Undated; cuid33233; 366418 (Box 5, Item 226-138)
  - Interview: "Their Cause Was Liberty Interview Irene Goldin Spiegel Vienna tape 2." 60-minute. Video Betacam SP., Nov 29, 1995; cuid33234; 366419 (Box 5, Item 226-139)
  - Interview: "Their Cause Was Liberty Interview Irene Goldin Spiegel Vienna tape 3." 60-minute. Video Betacam SP., Nov 29, 1995; cuid33235; 366420 (Box 5, Item 226-140)
  - Interview: "Their Cause Was Liberty Interview Irene Goldin Spiegel Vienna tape 5." 60-minute. Video Betacam SP., Nov 29, 1995; cuid33236; 366421 (Box 5, Item 226-141)
  - Interview: "Their Cause Was Liberty Interview Irene Goldin Spiegel Vienna tape 6." 60-minute. Video Betacam SP., Nov 29, 1995; cuid33237; 366422 (Box 5, Item 226-142)
  - Interview: "Their Cause Was Liberty Interview Irene Goldin Spiegel Vienna tape 7." 60-minute. Video Betacam SP., Nov 29, 1995; cuid33238; 366423 (Box 5, Item 226-143)
  - Interview: "Their Cause Was Liberty Interview Irene Goldin Spiegel Vienna tape 8." 60-minute. Video Betacam SP., Nov 29, 1995; cuid33239; 366424 (Box 5, Item 226-144)
  - Interview: "Their Cause Was Liberty Interview Irene Goldin Spiegel Vienna tape 9." 60-minute. Video Betacam SP., Nov 29, 1995; cuid33240; 366425 (Box 5, Item 226-145)
  - Archival footage: "Fox Movietonews Exemplary Films Spanish War tape 1." 60-minute. Video Betacam SP. (Original from Fox Movietone.), Undated; cuid33241; 366426 (Box 5, Item 226-146)
  - Archival footage: "Fox Movietonews Exemplary Films Spanish War tape 2." 60-minute. Video Betacam SP. (Original from Fox Movietone.), Undated; cuid33242; 366427 (Box 5, Item 226-147)
  - Archival footage: "Fox Movietonews Exemplary Films Spanish War tape 4." 60-minute. Video Betacam SP. (Original from Fox Movietone.), Undated; cuid33243; 366428 (Box 5, Item 226-148)
  - Archival footage: "Fox Movietonews Exemplary Films Spanish War tape 5." 60-minute. Video Betacam SP. (Original from Fox Movietone.), Undated; cuid33244; 366429 (Box 5, Item 226-149)
  - Archival footage: "Spanish Civil War." 60-minute. Video Betacam SP., Undated; cuid33245; 366430 (Box 5, Item 226-150)
  - Archival footage: "Guernica Guerre D'Espagne." 60-minute. Video Betacam SP. (Original from Cinemateque Gaumont.), Undated; cuid33246; 366431 (Box 5, Item 226-151)
  - Archival footage: "Lincoln Brigade Women Brig #2." 60-minute. Video Betacam SP., Undated; cuid33247; 366432 (Box 5, Item 226-152)
  - Archival footage: "Leves Aaant le Jour." 60-minute. Video Betacam SP. (Original from Cine-Archives.), Undated; cuid33248; 366433 (Box 5, Item 226-153)
  - Video: "Salaria Kee (a.ka. Salaria Kea, later O'Reilly) CR 194-196 Wild Sound." 60-minute. Betacam SP., Apr 20, 2000; cuid33249; 366434 (Box 6, Item 226-154, Dvd 226-154)
  - Video: "Salaria Kee (a.ka. Salaria Kea, later O'Reilly) CR 191-193 Wild Sound." 60-minute. Betacam SP., Apr 20, 2000; cuid33250; 366435 (Box 6, Item 226-155, Dvd 226-155)
  - Archival footage: "Hearts of Spain." 60-minute. Video Betacam SP., Feb 25, 1999; cuid33251; 366436 (Box 6, Item 226-156)